<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Some Personal Notes</title><link>https://black-puppydog.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/feeds/all.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Why Facebook Keeps Switching You to "Top Stories"</title><link>https://black-puppydog.github.io/why-facebook-keeps-switching-you-to-top-stories.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tl;dr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook earns money from you being on their crappy ranked "newsfeed".
It allows them to pressure businesses and artists into paying for your
otherwise free attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I fell for facebook's "Top Stories" again.
After scrolling through some pages of posts I realized I am seeing old and random stuff and, sure enough, facebook had decided to switch me back from "Most Recent" to "Top Stories" &lt;em&gt;yet again&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already knowing the answer I decided nevertheless to search for a solution this time around.
Of course, I am not the only one who hates this "feature" and so the facebook support forums are full of posts like this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/help/community/question/?id=776631003679"&gt;How do I stop Facebook from changing my preferences to top stories?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No answer here of course. But then again the quesition is not the right one.
This one is much closer to the heart of the issue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/help/community/question/?id=786826244683755"&gt;Why does my news feed keep changing to Top Stories?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the facebook support pages aren't exactly known for their in-depth discussions of technical and business issues, so the "answers" in that thread are not exactly help- or insightful.
The actualy answer boils down to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By controlling what you see, facebook is able to sell your attention to advertisers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their business model these days goes a bit like this:
if you start a new business, blog, podcast or whatever else you'll quickly gain traction and followers on facebook.
Your posts will propagate quickly through the social network, be seen and shared and it will feel great and potentially earn you money.
But then, when facebook thinks that they have become an essential part of your business model, that you depend on the likes and shares for whatever you are doing, then you will have to pay for actually getting your content to your audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does that work? "Top Stories", that's how.
Imagine (or remember) a facebook as it was before top stories were introduced.
You would see exactly everything that the people and pages you follow had posted, in chronoligical order.
That means that a pot would get seen by people if and only if it was shared and reshared by enough people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With top stories enabled on (supposedly) the majority of accounts, this does not hold any longer.
Even if your post is brilliant and everyone who sees it shares it that does not mean anything if facebook does not &lt;em&gt;show&lt;/em&gt; it to people because their ranking algorithm decided it is not "interesting" enough.
Or because you haven't paid your monthly fee...
So, not so many shares, even fewer reshares, and so on.
Your post becomes irrelevant.
But then again, you could pay 10 or 20 bucks to change it back to the way it was for a while, couldn't you?
If that reminds you of a classic mob shakedown, that's not by accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So facebook has a strong incentive to have as many people use "Top Stories" as possible at any given time.
What you see is not really tailored to what they believe you want to see. 
It is actually just a way for facebook to use you to pressure others into paying for your attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daan Wynen</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2016-02-03:why-facebook-keeps-switching-you-to-top-stories.html</guid><category>web</category><category>facebook</category></item><item><title>All Remedies Available, Part II</title><link>https://black-puppydog.github.io/all-remedies-available-part-ii.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today Ars Technica has a short &lt;a href="http://arstechnica.co.uk/tech-policy/2015/05/uk-government-quietly-rewrites-hacking-laws-to-grant-gchq-immunity/"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; about a new law "that exempts GCHQ, police, and other intelligence officers from prosecution for hacking into computers and mobile phones."
Effectively this makes (some of) the things that Edward Snowden made us aware of legal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why would the public accept this kind of thing to pass?
Why didn't we hear about this earlier?
How come this was not a hot topic for debate?
That's the thing with this law: nobody was told it even existed &lt;em&gt;until it was already in effect&lt;/em&gt;!
As Ars Technica points out, this is legal.
That is, the current (and past) laws in the UK allow for this kind of thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But secret laws are (another) way the UK government is rapidly deconstructing their image as a democratic group, i.e. a group that practices democratic procedures in the public interest.
Apart from government, intelligence and law enforcement agencies, nobody could influence this legislation.
So who is being represented here?
For me, a government that does this kind of thing loses its legitimacy, full stop.
And this becomes even more drastic seeing that this bit of news breaks just a week after the elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about this in the context of my short look at the &lt;a href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/camerons-dystopia.html"&gt;right to resistance&lt;/a&gt; from Thursday:
When have we used the available remedies?
Well, for a law that atacks the individual's freedoms, is passed in secret, and held secret until in effect, there are &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; few in the first place..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this kind of action the UK government makes it easy to pursue arguments that legitimize extremist actions by taking away most of, if not all, remedies that would be available through a proper democratic debate.
If that was not their intention then they should revoke this law, enter it into the proper parliamentary process and pass it with a vote the public can see and judge them by.
If it &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; their intention, then the UK would already be it's own version of 1984 that easily legitimizes any act against Big Brother.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daan Wynen</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-05-17:all-remedies-available-part-ii.html</guid><category>Democracy</category><category>GCHQ</category><category>UK</category></item><item><title>Cameron's Dystopia</title><link>https://black-puppydog.github.io/camerons-dystopia.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When I first read about this in the &lt;a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/britain-is-too-tolerant-and-should-interfere-more-in-peoples-lives-says-david-cameron-10246517.html"&gt;Independent&lt;/a&gt; I thought they must have gotten something wrong.
But no, &lt;a href="https://firstlook.org/theintercept/2015/05/13/greatest-threat-free-speech-comes-terrorism-claiming-fight/"&gt;The Intercept&lt;/a&gt; and the Guardian heard the same words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This actually seems to be David Cameron's stance on what a democracy should look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For too long, we have been a passively tolerant society, saying to our citizens 'as long as you obey the law, we will leave you alone.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's right, being within your rights to do something is no longer an excuse for doing it.
To enforce this outrageous attack on democracy you obviously would need to control what people think, or rather which kind of opinion can even spread and thus (to an extent) which kind of thoughts can form in your &lt;strike&gt;subordinates'&lt;/strike&gt; citizens' minds.
Here you go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim is to catch not just those who spread or incite hatred on the grounds of gender, race or religion but also those who undertake harmful activities for the “purpose of overthrowing democracy”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They would include a ban on broadcasting and a requirement to submit to the police in advance any proposed publication on the web and social media or in print&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tory Home Secretary Theresa May, in context of what would constitute "extremism" only talks about people who "undermine our British values" and being "together as one society, One Nation."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greenwald:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally believe this was all more lyrical in its original German&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I agree. Also, some of the politicians giving the original speeches had much more charisma...
But the point is: Germany learned from this experience. 
So even if it obviously doesn't apply in the UK, let's have a look at that.
The German constitution contains an unamendable paragraph that deals with the very issue Cameron and his thugs claim to address: 
"overthrowing democracy":&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Germans shall have the right to resist any person seeking to abolish this constitutional order, if no other remedy is available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's right: Cameron's plan, if implemented, could easily fall under Germany's right to resistance &lt;em&gt;and vice versa&lt;/em&gt;!
A citizen fighting for their right to free expression could easily be labelled an extremist and faced with who knows what kind of treatment (&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/law/2014/jul/22/terrorism-law-targets-words-guns-bombs"&gt;David Miranda&lt;/a&gt; might have a word to say about that) because fundamentally disagreeing with your government is supposedly the most unbritish thing one could do.
But look at the issue from the other direction, the one expressed in the German constitution, and you get the complete opposite.
The UK government wants to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;outlaw opinions - even those expressed in a civil, nonviolent manner - and brand those expressing them "extremists". Which opinions? Unbritish ones!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make submission to the police of virtually &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; content &lt;em&gt;before publication&lt;/em&gt; mandatory (But "only" for people who have drawn attention before. And remember, the UK does not protect the freedom of the press in their constitution)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reintroduce laws for data retention under the "&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Draft_Communications_Data_Bill"&gt;Snoopers' Charter&lt;/a&gt;". Because, how else would epople "draw attention"? Due process or what?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a lawyer, but I am German. And funnily, that gives me an edge here for once.
After years of history lessons in highschool, criminalizing "unbritish" behaviour &lt;em&gt;and opinions&lt;/em&gt; for me is a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; red flag in terms of "overthrowing democracy". &lt;br/&gt;
But when is it really okay to conclude that the government has indeed set out to abolish democracy?
Where is the red line? &lt;br/&gt;
There is one more caveat with the right to resistance: you need to have used all other remedies.
When can you claim to have used the remedies available to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take this &lt;a href="http://www.spiegel.de/netzwelt/netzpolitik/angela-merkel-luegt-dem-volk-ist-es-egal-lobo-kolumne-a-1033577.html"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; (in German, sorry) by Sascha Lobo, incidentally also from yesterday.
Lobo complains (IMHO rightfully) that all the free press, all the evidence against our politicians is worthless if people can not be mobilized to vote those politicians out of office.
When the people disagreeing with the current government see no alternatives, when they are so disillusioned with politics as a whole that they see no point in trying to change anything, then the best evidence of even criminal actions &lt;em&gt;by our government&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;against us&lt;/em&gt; will remain without consequence.
The "fourth estate" becomes an exercise in futility.
And also, a population that cannot be bothered to vote loses its right to resistance.
You could have voted your tyrants out of power you lazy bums!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- ![Guy Fawkes Mask]({filename}/images/2015&amp;#45;05&amp;#45;14_guy_fawkes.jpg) --&gt;

&lt;figure style="float: right"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Original Guy Fawks mask from V for Vendetta" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-05-14_guy_fawkes.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt; &lt;a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Original_Guy_Fawks_mask_from_V_for_Vendetta_%285400848923%29.jpg" &gt;CC-BY Enrique Dans&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the case of the UK, the plans are published just days &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the election.
By the time of the next election, publicly fighting such core British values as internet, media and thought censorship might already be illegal.
And those opposing the law now?
Well, they are against a law aiming to catch "those who spread or incite hatred on the grounds of gender, race or religion".
They should probably submit their social media posts to the police for good measure.
So where's the remedy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's hope people won't have to remember where those masks came from.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daan Wynen</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-05-14:camerons-dystopia.html</guid><category>Cameron</category><category>UK</category><category>Free Speech</category></item><item><title>Das Problem ist der Wütende Mob!</title><link>https://black-puppydog.github.io/altenbockum-erklaert-den-mob-zum-problem.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Für die, dies es nicht mitbekommen haben: &lt;a href="http://www.spiegel.de/politik/deutschland/ueberwachung-neue-spionageaffaere-erschuettert-bnd-a-1030191.html"&gt;Spiegel Online&lt;/a&gt; berichtete am Donnerstag darüber, dass der BND jahrelang &lt;em&gt;wissentlich&lt;/em&gt; Selektoren der NSA verheimlicht hat, die klar gegen europäische und deutsche Ziele gerichtet waren, und nicht etwa gegen Terroristen oder dergleichen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In der &lt;a href="http://www.faz.net/aktuell/politik/kommentar-der-bnd-im-circus-maximus-13557254.html"&gt;FAZ&lt;/a&gt; erklärt Japser von Altenbockum, was das eigentliche Problem derzeit ist:
Es ist nicht etwa das Auspionieren von Europäischen und Deutschen Unternehmen, Politikern und (IMHO stets unterbewertet) Privatpersonen, nein.
Genau genommen gibt es eigentlich gar kein Problem. 
Der BND hat sich nur im falschen Augenblick einen Fauxpas geleistet, indem er der Bundesregierung nichts von den Selektoren gesagt hat, die klar nichts mit Terrorismus zu tun hatten.
Das macht den Mob - die "aufgepeitschte Öffentlichkeit" - wütend, das war "eine Dummheit".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dieser Artikel macht mich sauer, und das gleich aus mehreren Gründen.
Gleich zu Beginn stellt Altenbockum den Strohmann auf, die NSA sei "die größte Bedrohung der deutschen Sicherheit" und schießt diesen dann folgermaßen nieder:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ohne diese Zusammenarbeit wäre die Sicherheit Deutschlands gefährdet. Da das so ist, haben alle diese Angriffe für die Arbeit des BND untergeordnete Bedeutung. Viel wichtiger sind: Russland, China, Terror. Ein Versäumnis in dieser Richtung wäre weit gravierender als alle bisher bekannt gewordenen Versäumnisse des BND an der Seite der NSA zusammengenommen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wohlgemerkt schreibt er &lt;em&gt;nicht&lt;/em&gt;, dass das schon alles seine Ordnung gehabt hätte.
Sondern er sagt im Grunde "aber wir können uns im Kampf gegen den Terror (und Russland und China) von solchen Kleinlichkeiten wie geltendem Recht nicht aufhalten lassen."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Das alleine wäre mir schon zuwider, denn mit desem Statement hätte Herr von Altenbockum auch einfach Regierungssprecher werden können.
Aber dann macht er sich noch nicht einmal die Mühe, das vernünftig auszuformulieren.
"Russland, China, Terror."
Bloß nicht zu kompliziert, der Mob braucht schließlich ein klar definiertes Feindbild.
Alles andere verwirrt den Mob nur, könnte ihn gar aufpeitschen.
Daher auch gleich noch eine Ansage dazu, was von den bisherigen Veröffentlichungen zu halten ist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alle sensationsheischenden Einblicke in die Welt von BND und NSA mussten zudem – nicht ganz so öffentlichkeitswirksam – korrigiert werden. &lt;a href="http://www.faz.net/aktuell/politik/harte-bretter/ueberwachungsstaat-deutschland-in-der-snowden-falle-13459674.html"&gt;Manche „Massenüberwachung“ entpuppte sich als pure Chimäre&lt;/a&gt;, ohne dass deren Enthüller das bis heute wahrhaben wollten. Auch im jetzt wieder aufgewärmten Fall ist das so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh? Ist das so? Da hängt ein Link dran, das muss ja dann eine Quelle sein, andere Links gibt es im ganzen Kommentar nicht.
Nun, der Link führt zu einem weiteren Kommentar von von Altenbockum, vom 5.3.2015.
In diesem Kommentar stellt er fest, dass im Grunde alles, was Greenwald und andere Journalisten veröffentlichten, Unfug ist.
Eine Quelle dafür gibt er nur in einem Fall: den Gemalto-Hack.
Als Hinweis dafür, dass es sich hierbei ja nur um einen Plan gehandlet haben könnte und nicht etwa um eine vollzogene Attacke, verweist er auf den "Blogger Rolf Weber".
Dieser schrieb im Wesentlichen "seht her, die interessieren sich ja vor allem für SIMs aus dem Iran, Pakistan etc, also alles kein Problem" und berief sich dabei auf &lt;a href="https://firstlook.org/theintercept/document/2015/02/19/imsis-identified-ki-data-network-providers-jan10-mar10-trial/"&gt;eine Folie des GHCQ&lt;/a&gt; (Kopie &lt;a href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-04-26_gemalto_2.pdf"&gt;hier&lt;/a&gt;).
Das als Ausrede gelten zu lassen ist schon ein starkes Stück, vor allem, wenn man sich eine weitere - ebenfalls vom Intercept veröffentlichte - &lt;a href="https://firstlook.org/theintercept/document/2015/02/19/cne-access-core-mobile-networks-2/"&gt;Folie&lt;/a&gt; ( &lt;a href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-04-26_gemalto.pdf"&gt;Kopie&lt;/a&gt;) ansieht:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GEMALTO - successfully implanted several machines and
believe we have their entire network - TDSD are working the
data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Wir haben das gesamte Netz."
Nur gut, dass wir uns darauf verlassen können, dass sie nicht hinter uns her sind, schließlich ist Gemalto der weltweit größte Hersteller von SIM-Karten.
Wann und warum die anderen angesprochenen Enthüllungen - Prism und Boundless Informant werden als Beipsiele gegeben - so nicht stimmen, wird gar nicht weiter belegt. Muss man ja auch nicht, das hier reicht da schon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Falsch war auch, dass die NSA direkten Zugang zu den Servern amerikanischer Internetkonzerne wie Apple oder Google hatte („Prism“)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noch Fragen? Keine? Gut, dann jetzt zurück zum Kommentar von letztem Freitag, 24.4.
Nachdem Altenbockum mit Hinweis auf seine eigenen, größtenteils unbelegten Aussagen, klargestellt hat, dass es kein Problem gibt, kann man dann ja der Linkspartei "politische Geschmacklosigkeit" und Antiamerikanismus vorzuwerfen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im letzten Absatz macht von Altenbockum dann noch einmal klar, was genau man dem BND vorwerfen sollte und was nicht, und nebenbei wiederholt er noch einmal wie gefährlich die Lage für Deutschland doch ist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Das Kanzleramt über faule NSA-Eier nicht zu informieren, mag angesichts der wahren Bedrohungslage Deutschlands verständlich gewesen sein. Doch allein, dass die SPD die Gelegenheit nutzt, die Kanzlerin zu schwächen, kann der BND-Spitze schon aus Eigeninteresse nicht gleichgültig sein. Angesichts der politischen Bedrohungslage des Kanzleramts war es deshalb eine Dummheit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soso, es war mag also verständlich gewesen sein, die Regierung &lt;em&gt;nicht&lt;/em&gt; auf klar gegen Deutsche und Europäische Interessen gerichtete Abfragen der NSA hinzuweisen und ihr damit die Basis zu einer echten Entscheidungsgrundlage zu nehmen?
Da muss man doch sogleich an einen Satz aus dem Absatz direkt darüber denken:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ein Geheimdienst, der sich gegen den eigenen Staat richtet und der sich dessen Kontrolle entzieht, ist ein Risiko für jede freie Gesellschaft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wenn unser eigener Nachrichtendienst es nicht für berichtenswert hält, dass unsere vermeintlich Verbündeten ihn zu Spionagezwecken &lt;em&gt;gegen uns selber&lt;/em&gt; missbrauchen, dann haben wir ein großes Problem. 
Journalisten wie Herr von Altenbockum, die in ihrem Glauben an das Wohlwollen der USA und unserer eigenen Dienste so aufgehen, dass sie deren Parolen (Bedrohungslage! Bedrohliche Bedrohungslage!) und Feindbilder (China! Russland! Terror!) dermaßen unhinterfragt und überspitzt wiederholen, sind ebenfalls Teil des Problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ach und der Mob ist auch nicht wütend. Das ist Zorn.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daan Wynen</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-04-26:altenbockum-erklaert-den-mob-zum-problem.html</guid><category>NSA</category><category>BND</category><category>FAZ</category></item><item><title>Typing French Characters in GTK Applications</title><link>https://black-puppydog.github.io/french-characters.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Since I will need to write some French accents every now and again in the future but I ususally work on a UK or US keyboard layout I collected these Unicode codes.
According to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_orthography"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; this should be enough to type any character you encounter in French.
I wrote everything on a piece of paper, then immediately spilled a cup of coffee over it.
So I thought a blog post was in order, both for my own reference and for others who might need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These codes work in any &lt;a href="http://www.gtk.org/"&gt;GTK&lt;/a&gt; application, which luckily includes &lt;a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/desktop/"&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/thunderbird"&gt;Thunderbird&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://pidgin.im/"&gt;Pidgin&lt;/a&gt;, i.e. just about the only three applications where I might care to use accents and all that stuff. :)
The only other application I really need is a terminal, and I use the Gnome terminal emulator for that, which also uses GTK.
So between these applications I think 99% of my computer time is covered and I won't bother to find out how to properly type these accents in any other way :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to use the Codes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In GTK you enter Unicode characters by pressing &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Shift+U&lt;/code&gt;, then typing the character code, then pressing &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt;.
Alternatively you can hold the &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Shift+U&lt;/code&gt; combination while typing the code and then just release it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Combining Codes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unicode allows the composition of characters.
So for the most cases you can actually get away with a few codes that only represent the "decorations".
To use these, you first type whichever character you want to decorate (say a 'U') and then enter the code (say 327) afterwards (i.e. with the cursor placed &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the 'U') and voilà, you get 'U̧'. &lt;br/&gt;
Helpful, I know :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here are the combining characters for accents and the diaeresis, aka umlaut:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Combining Symbol&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Grave Accent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;301&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Acute Accent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;302&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Circumflex Accent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;308&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Diaeresis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;327&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cedilla&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ligatures: Æ and Œ&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are not combinations of symbols, so you need to know their codes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Symbol&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;e6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;æ&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;c6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Æ&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;153&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;œ&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;152&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Œ&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Shorter Codes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some symbols (think 'ç', 'é', 'è', 'à') are more common than others, so you might want to remember these (shorter) codes separately.
The &lt;a href="https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Table_des_caract%C3%A8res_Unicode_(0000-0FFF)"&gt;Unicode tables&lt;/a&gt; for characters are loooooong so I collected the symbols used in French into this shorter table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;A&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;a&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;E&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;e&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;I&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;i&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;O&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;o&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;U&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;u&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Y&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;y&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Acute&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;c9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;e9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Grave&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;c1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;e1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;c8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;e8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;d9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;f9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Circumflex&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;c2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;e2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ca&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ea&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ce&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;d4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;f4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;db&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;fb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Diaeresis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;cb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;eb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;cf&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ef&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;dc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;fc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;178&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ff&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Or if you just came here to copy/paste a symbol, here you go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Codes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align="right"&gt;Symbols&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;c9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;e9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;e7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;c7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;c1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;e1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;c8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;e8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;d9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;f9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;c2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;e2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ca&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;ea&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ce&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;ee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;d4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;f4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;db&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;fb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;cb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;eb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;cf&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;ef&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;dc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;fc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;178&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;ff&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
M̀ȩ l̈ík̀êş! ʘ‿ʘ&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daan Wynen</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-04-26:french-characters.html</guid><category>unicode</category><category>GTK</category><category>linux</category><category>ubuntu</category></item><item><title>French Media on the Arrest of (yet another) Artist</title><link>https://black-puppydog.github.io/zeon.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Have you heard of Zeon?
Well, I heard about him today, &lt;a href="http://nonalignedmedia.com/2015/03/french-cartoonist-zeon-arrested-anti-zionist-work/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short version: he makes cartoons.
Which is what he got arrested for.
Or rather, for hatespeech. In his cartoons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you might disagree with his views, the whole Charlie affair should still be fresh enough for people to remember what this freedom of expression stuff is supposed to mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link above is from &lt;strong&gt;March 4&lt;/strong&gt; so by now this kind of case should have been properly discussed by the media.
So, these are the search results (from today, &lt;strong&gt;March 26&lt;/strong&gt;, 2015) for &lt;strong&gt;"Zeon"&lt;/strong&gt; in the French mainstream media as defined by &lt;a href="http://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Presse_en_France"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Le Parisien&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Le Parisien" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_leparisien.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are close! But not quite the right artist...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Le Figaro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Le Figaro" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lefigaro.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Le Monde&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Le Monde" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lemonde.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;L'Équipe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="L'Équipe" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lequipe.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I didn't really expect to find anything relevant there...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Les Échos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Les Échos" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lesechos.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Libération&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Libération" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_liberation.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;La Croix&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="La Croix" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lacroix.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;L'Humanité&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="L'Humanité" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lhumanite.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charlie Wassissname again?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daan Wynen</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-03-26:zeon.html</guid><category>Free Speech</category><category>France</category><category>Media</category></item><item><title>Google shows Ethymology for words</title><link>https://black-puppydog.github.io/google-shows-ethymology-for-words.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This may be ancient but I only really noticed this now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="This is something I have been waiting for for a while" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-02-17_google_ethymology.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note the diagram!
Another field where Google beats the community.
I have been craving for years for a good source on ethymological knowledge on the web.
Wikipedia has some infos on some words wherever the authors thought it worthwhile, but it is patchy and far from complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thumbs up Google! Or, +1, or you know, whatever... :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daan Wynen</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-02-17:google-shows-ethymology-for-words.html</guid><category>Google</category><category>Ethymology</category><category>Language</category><category>Web</category></item><item><title>User Tracking goes deeper than Ads</title><link>https://black-puppydog.github.io/subscription-based-publishing-wont-solve-tracking-and-profiling.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This is just something I picked up some time ago while attending &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lukOlejnik"&gt;Łukasz Olejnik&lt;/a&gt;'s PhD defense "Measuring the Privacy Risks and Value of Web Tracking".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He basically said that the problem with the advertising market form a privacy perspective is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the advertising itself but the tracking and profiling that comes with it.
Obvious as that might seem, in my mind I had always thrown the two into the same pot, probably also because after years without a TV or thelike I am easily annoyed by any advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this simple insight leads Łuskasz to another one that is more profound:&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Getting rid of the ads won't automatically solve the privacy issues.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscription-based publishing is one of the alternatives to advertising and often presented as more privacy-friendly.
But what would happen if this model actually got adopted on a larger scale?
Most probably, according to Łukasz, third-party services would quickly emerge to handle the subscription-management across sites.
And just like that there would a very similar situation as before:
A handful of people/companies would know who pays for which subscriptions, reads which articles, loads which images.
Just like today's advertising industry they would be able to track and profile through cookies and &lt;a href="https://panopticlick.eff.org/"&gt;all other means available&lt;/a&gt;.
It would just look less annoying because of the missing ads.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daan Wynen</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-02-13:subscription-based-publishing-wont-solve-tracking-and-profiling.html</guid><category>Web</category><category>Privacy</category></item><item><title>Holy Crap, I am Dangerous!</title><link>https://black-puppydog.github.io/am-i-a-terrorist.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;According to this list from the French Government I am in high
danger to become a jihadist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://static2.stop-djihadisme.gouv.fr/var/stop/storage/images/media/images/radicalisation/607-6-fre-FR/radicalisation.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="A handy list to check if everyone around you will become a jihadist." class="align-right" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-02-04_france_radicalisation.png" style="width: 30%;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So do both of us a favor and report me,
will you? Not convinced? Let me walk you through the list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-keep-a-distance-to-my-former-friends-because-i-consider-them-impure"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I keep a distance to my former friends (because I consider them &amp;quot;impure&amp;quot;)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True, I recently moved to a different country, so that might be it.
Except, you don't &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; why I left everyone behind...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-reject-family-members"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I reject Family Members&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't talked to some of them in &lt;em&gt;months&lt;/em&gt;. Sure, I would say I feel
bad about that. But would you believe someone who so obviously doesn't
give a jihadist shit about his family?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-brutally-changed-my-eating-habits"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I brutally changed my eating habits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I may or may not have changed from &amp;quot;cook your own meals to take to
work&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;eat in the canteen, then live off
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ramen"&gt;ramen&lt;/a&gt; at home.&amp;quot; But some of my
friends are also very suspicious: One of them recently stopped eating
meat &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; eggs &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; cheese &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; milk and really anything non-vegan!
Someone who keeps this kind of company... I mean, that's kind of extreme
to live in France and not eat Coq-au-Vin, cheese, baguette and more wine
every evening, isn't it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-don-t-watch-television-and-don-t-go-to-the-movies-anymore-because-they-show-images-i-consider-forbidden"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I don't watch television and don't go to the movies anymore (because they show images I consider forbidden)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait, I say, it's just that 99% of TV is bullshit or just plain shit.
Not worth spending a single second on. And I stay at work too late to go
to the movies. And my French is not good enough anyway... Ha, you say,
what pitiful pretexts to avoid sinful imagery! And right you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-stopped-doing-sports-because-it-is-mixed-gender"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I stopped doing Sports (because it is mixed-gender)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or because I am a classic Computer Science nerd who's idea of a good
evening can involve lengthy research on a topic remotely relevant to nothing, really,
followed by a rant on some remote social network most
people have not even heard of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I score &lt;strong&gt;6 out of 9&lt;/strong&gt; on this list, and &amp;quot;started wearing
clothes that cover the whole body&amp;quot; doesn't really count when Grenoble is
just having the first real snow.
Also I am not a women! (you can note this as &amp;quot;has medieval understanding of gender equality&amp;quot;)
So I guess I am pretty dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="but-wait-there-is-more"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;But wait, there is more!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="An icon of the false belief in total security." class="align-right" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-02-04_vigipirate.jpg" style="width: 200px;" /&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spend &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of time alone, thinking, reading, writing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I definitely have a problem with authority. I am &lt;em&gt;outraged&lt;/em&gt; by the
pointless demonstration of... of what, really?... at the entry door
at work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I live in a students accommodation, but I hardly meet my neighbors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, I could try and explain all of these points away, but let's
face it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The Red Menace is real! Report all suspected communist activity!" class="align-left" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-02-04_red_menace.jpg" style="height: 200px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This list is BULLSHIT&lt;/strong&gt; because it assumes you to know the motivation
behind someone's actions.
If you don't, it conveniently delivers the &amp;quot;correct&amp;quot; interpretation with the observations.
Sure, the disclaimer &lt;em&gt;at the bottom of the page&lt;/em&gt; notes that every case has to be treated individually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But overall, this kind of list makes any &amp;quot;unnormal&amp;quot; behaviour suspicious in and of itself.
The mindset this list promotes runs counter to the idea of individualism that I love so much about our western values or what they are supposed to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list only serves to spread &lt;strong&gt;Fear, Uncertainty and Doubt&lt;/strong&gt;.
But then, that's what a sleeper terrorist would say, wouldn't he?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, that's also what a communist would say around 1920 or during
the McCarthy era.
Or a witch a few hundred years before that...
Recommended reading of the day: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Crucible"&gt;The Crucible&lt;/a&gt; by Arthur Miller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt;
To the people shouting &amp;quot;Daan, don't be paranoid, nobody is going to say you're a terrorist&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point here was to demonstrate that this list can be applied to nearly anyone.
And when it comes to terrorists, a perceived intention seems to be good enough nowadays to treat you like one.
That means that this kind of criteria can easily be applied to people sho don't fit the social norm, or to anyone else, to make them &amp;quot;disappear&amp;quot; from public opinion.
In Germany they now want to take away passports of people &lt;em&gt;they think might want to&lt;/em&gt; leave to fight for IS/SIS/ISIL.
These people would then get a &amp;quot;replacement&amp;quot; passport which is basically saying &amp;quot;we think this person might be  a terrorist.&amp;quot;
Good luck getting a job with one o these.
How would you feel if the country you lived in took away your passport and branded you a dengerous person?
Chances are, you would be angry, aren't they?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, making people snitch on others for not fitting social norms &lt;em&gt;based on a perceived intention&lt;/em&gt; is dangerous because it will marginalize these people and may very well create the very aggression against society it is supposed to stifle.
But then again, that's the essence of the War on Terror™: you fight it with extreme means, so that you can be sure to prove yourself right in saying there are lots of enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daan Wynen</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-02-04:am-i-a-terrorist.html</guid><category>Terrorism</category><category>France</category><category>Bullshit</category><category>FUD</category></item><item><title>The Distributed Hash Table: Twister's Second Layer</title><link>https://black-puppydog.github.io/twister-dht.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When reading about twister, the three layer model often comes up.
It roughly goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blockchain for identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DHT for mutable information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Torrent for write-only content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I am going to look at the second layer because the Distributed Hash Table (DHT) is a fascinating invention and because people (including me) tend to have trouble wrapping their head around how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with my last post, I am learning about these things myself at the moment.
So if you find things that are unclear, incomplete or plain wrong, please tell me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First let us be clear what the task of the DHT is.
&lt;strong&gt;What does and does not go into the DHT?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DHT primarily holds &lt;em&gt;mutable&lt;/em&gt; information such as user profiles, avatars as well as collaborative information such as mentions and hashtags.
While at this point it also stores most of twister's posts, this is not why it is needed. 
The torrent layer could (and does) handle the storing of posts as well, the use of the DHT for them is just a performance enhancement.
On the other side of "layer 2" lies the block chain which holds the "slow-moving" identity management.
The block chain manages who can use which username to post by associating a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wXB-V_Keiu8"&gt;public key&lt;/a&gt; with each username. 
My &lt;a href="https://black-puppydog.withknown.com/2015/a-quick-note-on-twisters-blocks"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; about the blocks shows some examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Regular Hash Table&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, the "distributed hash table" is just a distributed version of a "hash table", a common data structure for storing and looking up data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can store any &lt;em&gt;value&lt;/em&gt; in a hash table using a &lt;em&gt;key&lt;/em&gt;, and later you can retrieve it using the same key again.
For this to work, it &lt;em&gt;hashes&lt;/em&gt; the key with a &lt;em&gt;hash function&lt;/em&gt;, which is really just to say we derive some number from the key by which we can sort the keys.
This number does not even have to be unique.
Of course, if the key is already a number that is quite simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So fundamentally, a hash table has just two operations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;put(key, value)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;value = get(key)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Example: Address Book&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An address book is a really simple hash table.
Assuming you order your address book by last names...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The key of an entry is the person's last name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The value of an entry is the contact information like phone number, email etc, so basically a long string.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hash function is just "Given a family name, only look at its first letter".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say you want to store (i.e. add) a new contact. Say you want to add me, Daan Wynen, to your address book.
You run my family name through the hash function, which lets you directly skip ahead to the "W" page where you then just add me to the bottom of the "W" list.
You don't bother to sort that list, because there are only a handful of people there anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, when you want to look me up, you start the same way: look at my family name, see that it starts with "W", skip ahead to the "W" page.
Then you just run your finger down the list until you find me and you're done.
Much faster than keeping all contacts in one big list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Twister Stores in the DHT&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already said that the DHT stores things like profiles and hashtags.
But what does that really mean?
Well, as many things web, twister's data is really just a bunch of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JSON"&gt;json&lt;/a&gt; documents.
&lt;code&gt;twisterd&lt;/code&gt; allows us to store and retrieve these using the &lt;code&gt;dhtget&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;dhtput&lt;/code&gt; commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;./twisterd &lt;span class="nb"&gt;help &lt;/span&gt;dhtget
dhtget &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; &amp;lt;resource&amp;gt; &amp;lt;s&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;ingle&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;/m&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;ulti&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;timeout_ms&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;timeout_multi_ms&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;min_multi&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;./twisterd &lt;span class="nb"&gt;help &lt;/span&gt;dhtput
dhtput &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; &amp;lt;resource&amp;gt; &amp;lt;s&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;ingle&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;/m&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;ulti&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;value&amp;gt; &amp;lt;sig_user&amp;gt; &amp;lt;seq&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Here is an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;./twisterd dhtget black_puppydog profile s
&lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;p&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 63503,
            &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;seq&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 31,
            &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;target&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;n&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;black_puppydog&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;r&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;profile&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;t&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;s&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;,
            &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;time&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 1417107655,
            &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;v&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Hangs out here for the self-selecting group of people to follow.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;fullname&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Daan Wynen&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;location&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Grenoble, France&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;tox&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;52166FAEB07E85551AE5C567CB37C16B31FC9F6DDCF64D2DAC7A13D426DAB976224A9A737A3C&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;http://black-puppydog.withknown.com/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;,
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;sig_p&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;20fc80066bf07eb708d9ced08958de863f42351e60495046bced9a05afab698a9abacb7208cfc0d31635edb4357be93a1820e80ba40396226628ce6deb07dc57af&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;sig_user&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;black_puppydog&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The actual profile is held in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; field: Name, location and whatever else information the user has added.
The rest is bureaucracy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;height&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is the number of the newest block when this value was stored in the DHT.
This, together with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;time&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (which is a UNIX timestamp) establishes that I changed my profile at 2014-11-27T17:00:55 UTC.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;seq&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; increments every time this entry is changed. 
These three can be used to keep the DHT consistent: if some node has been disconnected for a few months and suddenly starts handing out outdated info, other nodes can simply discard it as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;target&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; element holds the key of the entry; &lt;em&gt;name&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;resource&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;type&lt;/em&gt;.
These are the ones we have to provide to &lt;code&gt;twisterd&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;username&lt;/code&gt; argument is also (ab)used for hashtags, which can be retrieved like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;./twisterd dhtget twister hashtag m &lt;span class="m"&gt;500&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="m"&gt;500&lt;/span&gt; 10
&lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;p&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 72459,
            &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;target&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;n&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;twister&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;r&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;hashtag&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;t&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;m&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;,
            &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;time&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 1423000508,
            &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;v&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;sig_userpost&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;1fd080fe37fd0c4a250005eebad68196ae62aa647ab0e3533bef7af87a5a8c3c2944ec7184bfb92dd18c439eaa4aefa3baf861a917f9c62006968c715fdd0bb292&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;userpost&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 72459,
                    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;k&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 519,
                    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;lastk&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 518,
                    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;msg&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;With the new Raspberry Pi 2 now running a #Bitcoin or #Twister Node is easily doable.  Only &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt; for a Twister node. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$75&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt; for a BTC node&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;n&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;avatarx&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;time&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 1423000508
                &lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;,
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;sig_p&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;1f3a3bf0b704085e77918f8a7c9304c1002fd277cbbc39aad5899ff007277d761eb60be7b87d316aefb8685a109336bed41918b3dddedee897aeb10f2418228618&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;sig_user&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;avatarx&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;,

...
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;s(ingle)/m(ulti)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; argument tells &lt;code&gt;twisterd&lt;/code&gt; if there is one unique value stored for this key or if multiple values can be stored in the DHT.
For hashtags, obviously any user should be able to store an entry, and we mostly want to retrieve more than one entry for a hashtag.
A profile on the other hand is unique to a user and thus only has one entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;sig_p&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;sig_user&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; let us verify that this entry was created by a certain user using the public key stored in the block chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if I want to update my profile to show off my brand-new pelican-powered blag, and I am even too smug to use the HTML interface, I can do so like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ profile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;    &amp;quot;bio&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;Hangs out here for the self-selecting group of people to follow.&amp;quot;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;    &amp;quot;fullname&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;Daan Wynen&amp;quot;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;    &amp;quot;location&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;Grenoble, France&amp;quot;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;    &amp;quot;tox&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;52166FAEB07E85551AE5C567CB37C16B31FC9F6DDCF64D2DAC7A13D426DAB976224A9A737A3C&amp;quot;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;    &amp;quot;url&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;http://black-puppydog.github.io&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s1"&gt;}&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;./twisterd dhtput black_puppydog profile s &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$profile&lt;/span&gt; black_puppydog 33
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;./twisterd dhtget black_puppydog profile s
&lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;p&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 72461,
            &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;seq&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 33,
            &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;target&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;n&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;black_puppydog&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;r&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;profile&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;t&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;s&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;,
            &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;time&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 1423003589,
            &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;v&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;bio&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Hangs out here for the self-selecting group of people to follow.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;fullname&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Daan Wynen&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;location&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Grenoble, France&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;tox&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;52166FAEB07E85551AE5C567CB37C16B31FC9F6DDCF64D2DAC7A13D426DAB976224A9A737A3C&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
                &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;http://black-puppydog.github.io&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;,
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;sig_p&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;1f0c58b58cb01b2819f375510eb9e851522e816891ad88772a2151691dfb410c4e1900594b35e45eaba590faff6c5b50ffcc53e258dd0a9809556f5779e3020d87&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;sig_user&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;black_puppydog&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;And sure enought, the new website also shows up in the HTML:
&lt;img alt="Yay, now everyone can marvel at my ramblings!" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-02-04_my_profile.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not too surprising since the HTML/JavaScript interface makes the exact same calls to the &lt;code&gt;twisterd&lt;/code&gt; running as server as does &lt;code&gt;twisterd&lt;/code&gt; itself when called with the &lt;code&gt;dhtget&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How the DHT Stores And Retrieves Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DHT was made popular by file sharing networks like BitTorrent.
If you have used BitTorrent's &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnet_URI_scheme"&gt;magnet links&lt;/a&gt; you have used a DHT to retrieve a .torrent file.
Back in the day, these .torrent files had to be hosted somewhere and you would have to download them before you could get that movie or .iso or whatever.
Now, with the DHT network, you just get the magnet link, which is a hash of the .torrent file. 
With this hash you then retrieve the file itself, so the hash of the file itself acts as the key to the file in the hash table.
Since the hash is long this key is assumed to be unique, an assumption that seems &lt;a href="https://crypto.stackexchange.com/questions/418/is-the-number-of-creatable-torrents-limited"&gt;reasonable enough&lt;/a&gt; given the numbers involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For twister, the situation is similar: the three inputs &lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;resource&lt;/code&gt; and one bit for &lt;code&gt;m&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;s&lt;/code&gt; are made into a joint sha1 hash that then gets used as the key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, when storing a key/value pair in the DHT, the question is which node(s) should store it.
Some naive strategies come to mind here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;every node stores every key/value pair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;only one random node stores every key/value pair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, these strategies are not very suitable to the task, but using them as examples we can clearly see what we would like the Best Strategy™ to look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If every node stores every entry, then looking up an entry is always fast, since it is already present on the node performing the search. We like that. 
But that would require that every node store every entry, which can be a lot of data.
And if an entry gets updated on one node, that change would have to propagate through the network, and until it would, other nodes would receive the old value when searching for the key. 
We don't like that...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if we store every pair on exactly one random node, then we save lots of storage space across the network, and also the bandwidth to send the data to every node!
We like that.
But then searching would take forever since we would have to ask &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; node if they hold the pair for the key we're searching for.
We don't like that for sure...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, twister does neither of those two.
In fact, twister just uses the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kademlia"&gt;Kademlia&lt;/a&gt; implementation of a DHT.
Kademlia, like any decent DHT implementation, assigns a &lt;em&gt;node ID&lt;/em&gt; to every node in the network, so in twister's case every twisterd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important part about these IDs is that they can be regarded as being in the same &lt;em&gt;space&lt;/em&gt; as the keys used for storage and retrieval.
One then defines a &lt;em&gt;distance function&lt;/em&gt; between keys and node IDs.
The idea is that only nodes &lt;em&gt;close to an entry's key&lt;/em&gt; store its data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Example: 2D Key Space&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine we would use a really simple distance function:
The keys and node IDs are both 40 bits long. 
We regard the first 20 bits as an x coordinate, and the second 20 bits as a y coordinate, and we divide both of them by 2^20 so all coordinates are in [0, 1].
The distance between two points (x1, y1) and (x2, y2) is then simply the (euclidean) distance between those points.
For example:
&lt;img alt="Some nodes covering the 2D key space" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-02-04_voronoi_1.png" /&gt;
Here the points &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; the polygons are the nodes and the areas around them are the regions of the key space they are responsible for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Retrieving Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &lt;code&gt;twisterd&lt;/code&gt; has created the sha1 hash of the key it starts &lt;em&gt;routing&lt;/em&gt; towards a node that holds the corresponding data.
For this, every node holds a &lt;em&gt;routing table&lt;/em&gt; of peers and their corresponding node IDs.
These are the DHT peers you can see on twister's Network page.
The lookup is an iterative process: on every iteration twisterd queries a node, starting with itself, for the given key.
If the current node is not responsible for the key because its node ID is not close enough to the key then the node being queried looks into its own routing table to find another node &lt;em&gt;that is closer to the key than itself&lt;/em&gt;.
So on every iteration twisterd queries a node that is closer to the key than the last one.
If the node being queried holds the key (or the *should hold it but it simply doesn't exist) then the process finishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Storing Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is actually quite trivial. &lt;code&gt;twisterd&lt;/code&gt; could simply send the new key/value pair to any of its peers.
Since the recipient could check if it is responsible for this key, it could decide whether to store it or to forward it to a node closer to the key.
But Kademlia is a bit cleverer than that.
Instead of relying on the forwarding mechanism it first finds a node close to the key, which is really just the same procedure as before for the look-up.
It then sends the new data this node, sparing the network a lot of forwarding messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Adding and Removing Nodes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People go on- and offline all the time.
For the DHT network that means that nodes suddenly appear and disappear.
When a node appears, it is allocated a region of the key space that it is responsible for, based on its node ID.
To stay with the simple example from above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Some nodes covering the 2D key space" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-02-04_voronoi_2.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what happens when a node disappears, maybe because the owner of the PC running this twister server is going to bed?
To prevent the data on this node from simply disappearing, every key is stored not only on one node, but on several nodes, and when a node disappears these responsibilities are renegotiated, just as they are when a node appears:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Some nodes covering the 2D key space" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-02-04_voronoi_3.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twister's DHT is a proven system for storing data in a decentralized manner.
Through the use of signatures and the public keys stored in the block chain each user keeps control over their profile information and other data.
And the principle behind the DHT is even quite simple to sum up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I cannot help you get what you want, I know a guy who can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope I got across the point that DHTs are fascinating and useful. If you like this post, please tell me.
If you think it sucked, please, tell me why!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daan Wynen</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-02-04:twister-dht.html</guid><category>DHT</category><category>twister</category></item><item><title>A Note on Twister Transactions</title><link>https://black-puppydog.github.io/twister-blocks.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This is just a quick note about what the blockchain does and does not store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't write this software, and I am mostly trying to make sense of it myself at the moment.
So if you find things that are unclear, incomplete or plain wrong, please tell me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The "what is not in the blockchain?" part is easy: anything that does not relate to user names, public keys, the spam messages or the blockchain itself lives &lt;em&gt;outside&lt;/em&gt; the blockchain.
Profiles and twists are stored in a Distributed Hash Table (DHT) and the twists also in a torrent swarm.
This is because storing all twists in the chain, although possible, would not scale.
A block chain is relatively slow, and more importantly, all nodes of the network would have to download and store &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; twists ever made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does the chain store, concretely?
You can find out by running some simple commands for your local twister daemon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's get a random block from the chain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;./twisterd getblockhash  71772
70b7f1bb37eb72d587f45457c5c0c0bdadd206f0115f66787d8565761688bd1d

&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;./twisterd getblock  70b7f1bb37eb72d587f45457c5c0c0bdadd206f0115f66787d8565761688bd1d
&lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;hash&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;70b7f1bb37eb72d587f45457c5c0c0bdadd206f0115f66787d8565761688bd1d&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;confirmations&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 38,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;size&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 361,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 71772,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;version&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 2,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;merkleroot&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;ba8dd4de438b296fe16f619f16a988700f1161fbba3fefadef7df14964823c7b&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;tx&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;1cd83cd3c6d4bc41099cc57bf592f2ce91470d09f364b5dda49c828474e2bcb9&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;0000001ba539c9045a906a8efe4b1fdbe916b925098cc58be422060e987df636&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;spamMessage&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Promoted posts are needed to run the network infrastructure. If you want to help, start generating blocks and advertise. [en]&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;spamUser&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;brunus&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;userhashes&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;6756f780590a51b6857104268c58c331b432b3d17290dbabd496c7f95c1033b0&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;usernames&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;kwofu&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;time&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 1422554853,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;nonce&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 4700834,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;bits&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;1d429ed8&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;difficulty&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 0.01501017,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;previousblockhash&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;6d36ace676ce6a8e600f31fa743eef7e96110c3713d9736f138cd864a9fa7c88&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;nextblockhash&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;8da5a51cf66ee39e0fb98dd5b137a19ec143d80e085083317c96e4ff36e8d149&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This is a human-readable representation of a block as it is stored in the blockchain.
The non-readable version is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;./twisterd getblock  70b7f1bb37eb72d587f45457c5c0c0bdadd206f0115f66787d8565761688bd1d &lt;span class="nb"&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;

020000005c180100887cfaa964d88c136f73d913370c11967eef3e74fa310f608e6ace76e6ac366d7b3c826449f17defadef3fbafb61110f7088a9169f616fe16f298b43ded48dbae576ca54d89e421da2ba470002010000007f4c7d50726f6d6f74656420706f73747320617265206e656564656420746f2072756e20746865206e6574776f726b20696e6672617374727563747572652e20496620796f752077616e7420746f2068656c702c2073746172742067656e65726174696e6720626c6f636b7320616e64206164766572746973652e205b656e5d4e066272756e7573411fe3902beb204364ffc5d89c6fec2bed2a13c6debeec22893fb088431dc426c8e164f42035c93c6de03b20f96cf86dfb0676e8c50b8cc83b94479e98a9685f2b7504997271c3090102062f503253482f00000000010000000006056b776f6675222103fccd1d6050f2abb9b8ece690672720600afccd553dfeb0dd23587d02601928a417033e00
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Let's stick with the readable version... :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of what you see here are things that take care of the blockchain itself. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;blockhash&lt;/code&gt; identifies this block&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;previousblockhash&lt;/code&gt; links it to its predecessor (hence the name "block&lt;em&gt;chain&lt;/em&gt;"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;difficulty&lt;/code&gt; controls how many values for &lt;code&gt;nonce&lt;/code&gt; need to be tried to generate a block. It gets adjusted automatically as a function of the &lt;code&gt;timestamps&lt;/code&gt; in the chain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this is all very fascinating, it is nothing specific to the Twister blockchain.
In fact, the only thing in which Twister significantly differs from the bitcoin chain is what the &lt;em&gt;transactions&lt;/em&gt; (or short: &lt;code&gt;tx&lt;/code&gt;) contain and what the miner gets for the mining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the transactions in Twister don't say "Alice just sent Bob 0.001 BTC" as they do for Bitcoin.
Rather they tell the Twister daemon who registered and what public key they are using.
So in block 71772 the user kwofu registered and that got recorded in the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;./twisterd getrawtransaction kwofu 1

&lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;hex&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;010000000006056b776f6675222103fccd1d6050f2abb9b8ece690672720600afccd553dfeb0dd23587d02601928a417033e00&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;txid&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;6756f780590a51b6857104268c58c331b432b3d17290dbabd496c7f95c1033b0&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;version&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 1,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;mess   age&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;username&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;kwofu&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;pubKey&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;03fccd1d6050f2abb9b8ece690672720600afccd553dfeb0dd23587d02601928a4&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;nonce&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 4064023,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;blockhash&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;70b7f1bb37eb72d587f45457c5c0c0bdadd206f0115f66787d8565761688bd1d&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 71772,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;confirmations&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 44,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;time&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 1422554853,
    &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;blocktime&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; : 1422554853
&lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;hex&lt;/code&gt; field contains all the information we see here, just more in a more compact encoding.
The &lt;code&gt;txid&lt;/code&gt; uniquely identifies this particular transaction.
&lt;code&gt;height&lt;/code&gt; tells us which block this transaction is a part of.
&lt;code&gt;username&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;pubkey&lt;/code&gt; are the part that we are actually interested in. Having the username and public key linked together by putting them into one transaction allows us to check if a particular twist from kwofu is actually signed with kwofu's key.
This is how Twister checks that nobody can pose as another user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mining part is fairly simple: a Bitcoin miner will get 1 BTC for successfully mining a block. A Twister miner gets to put their name and message into the block itself. Since these messages get stored on &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; daemon, they can be shown as advertisement to &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; user.
The idea is that every server and every client application will at least show some of them so that mining will actually be an attractive advertising option. 
Or maybe some other solution will be found to the question of "Who keeps the Twister network running?"
Who knows.
Anyway, spam messages can either be posted by &lt;code&gt;@nobody&lt;/code&gt; in which case the spam message will just be entered into the block by the miner and that's it.
Or it can be posted in the name of an existing account. For the above block, that was &lt;code&gt;@brunus&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;{
    &amp;quot;txid&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;0000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;version&amp;quot; : 1,
    &amp;quot;message&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;Promoted posts are needed to run the network infrastructure. If you want to help, start generating blocks and advertise. [en]&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;username&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;brunus&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;pubKey&amp;quot; : [
        &amp;quot;02&amp;quot;,
        &amp;quot;2f503253482f&amp;quot;
    ],
    &amp;quot;nonce&amp;quot; : 0,
    &amp;quot;blockhash&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;70b7f1bb37eb72d587f45457c5c0c0bdadd206f0115f66787d8565761688bd1d&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;height&amp;quot; : 71772,
    &amp;quot;confirmations&amp;quot; : 54,
    &amp;quot;time&amp;quot; : 1422554853,
    &amp;quot;blocktime&amp;quot; : 1422554853
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Although I am not quite sure why that &lt;code&gt;txid&lt;/code&gt; is always 0 for the spam transactions...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, hope this was interesting to someone else than me :P&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Daan Wynen</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 01:22:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-01-30:twister-blocks.html</guid><category>blockchain</category><category>twister</category></item></channel></rss>