<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Some Personal Notes</title><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://black-puppydog.github.io/</id><updated>2015-02-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>The Cost of Nonconformity</title><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/the-cost-of-nonconformity.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Daan Wynen</name></author><id>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-02-23:the-cost-of-nonconformity.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last November I started my masters thesis at INRIA Grenoble.
I have never been in France for longer than a month before, and even now it is a mere four months, so some culture clash is to be expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to write about one specific part of that: how a society caters to individual needs and behaviours and how it promotes social coherence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; I am not a scociologist, not at all. So I wouldn't even know if "social coherence" is the correct term to describe what I mean.
And also, this entire post will be 100% subjective, I have no data to back it up, and no intention to change that. 
This is entirely my opinion, no more and no less, and one reason I put it out there is for people to tell me I'm wrong and why.
So please, share your thoughts on this if you have any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now what do I mean by social coherence? I mostly mean &lt;em&gt;something that gives a definition of "us" and "them"&lt;/em&gt;.
To stick with my current situation: 
What would it really mean to be part of the French society?
Being born and raised in France, having French parents, this kind of definition does not fit into today's society, at least for most people, and luckily so I should say!
But if these criteria don't let us define an "us" anymore, what makes my neighbour be closer to me (mentally) than the starving kid somehwere in Africa?
Not that the latter is not worth the empathy, but on a day to day basis I will interact more with my colleagues and neighbours, and groups which are not held together by something that they &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; usually identify themselves as a group by something they &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt;.
A common language goes a long way here, and countries lacking this feature often struggle with it.
Common ethical and philosophical frameworks are another good foundation to build a coherent society on.
France, like many other countries is currently having a lot of debate about this issue since due to migration (and loads of opther reasons), larger and larger parts of the population just don't fall into the "French, catholic" drawer anymore.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Society"></category><category term="Individualism"></category></entry></feed>