<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Some Personal Notes</title><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/feeds/war-on-democracy.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://black-puppydog.github.io/</id><updated>2015-03-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>French Media on the Arrest of (yet another) Artist</title><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/zeon.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Daan Wynen</name></author><id>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-03-26:zeon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you heard of Zeon?
Well, I heard about him today, &lt;a href="http://nonalignedmedia.com/2015/03/french-cartoonist-zeon-arrested-anti-zionist-work/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short version: he makes cartoons.
Which is what he got arrested for.
Or rather, for hatespeech. In his cartoons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you might disagree with his views, the whole Charlie affair should still be fresh enough for people to remember what this freedom of expression stuff is supposed to mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link above is from &lt;strong&gt;March 4&lt;/strong&gt; so by now this kind of case should have been properly discussed by the media.
So, these are the search results (from today, &lt;strong&gt;March 26&lt;/strong&gt;, 2015) for &lt;strong&gt;"Zeon"&lt;/strong&gt; in the French mainstream media as defined by &lt;a href="http://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Presse_en_France"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Le Parisien&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Le Parisien" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_leparisien.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are close! But not quite the right artist...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Le Figaro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Le Figaro" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lefigaro.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Le Monde&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Le Monde" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lemonde.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;L'Équipe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="L'Équipe" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lequipe.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I didn't really expect to find anything relevant there...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Les Échos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Les Échos" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lesechos.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Libération&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Libération" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_liberation.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;La Croix&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="La Croix" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lacroix.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;L'Humanité&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="L'Humanité" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lhumanite.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charlie Wassissname again?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Free Speech"></category><category term="France"></category><category term="Media"></category></entry><entry><title>Holy Crap, I am Dangerous!</title><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/am-i-a-terrorist.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Daan Wynen</name></author><id>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-02-04:am-i-a-terrorist.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to this list from the French Government I am in high
danger to become a jihadist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://static2.stop-djihadisme.gouv.fr/var/stop/storage/images/media/images/radicalisation/607-6-fre-FR/radicalisation.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="A handy list to check if everyone around you will become a jihadist." class="align-right" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-02-04_france_radicalisation.png" style="width: 30%;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So do both of us a favor and report me,
will you? Not convinced? Let me walk you through the list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-keep-a-distance-to-my-former-friends-because-i-consider-them-impure"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I keep a distance to my former friends (because I consider them &amp;quot;impure&amp;quot;)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True, I recently moved to a different country, so that might be it.
Except, you don't &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; why I left everyone behind...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-reject-family-members"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I reject Family Members&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't talked to some of them in &lt;em&gt;months&lt;/em&gt;. Sure, I would say I feel
bad about that. But would you believe someone who so obviously doesn't
give a jihadist shit about his family?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-brutally-changed-my-eating-habits"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I brutally changed my eating habits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I may or may not have changed from &amp;quot;cook your own meals to take to
work&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;eat in the canteen, then live off
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ramen"&gt;ramen&lt;/a&gt; at home.&amp;quot; But some of my
friends are also very suspicious: One of them recently stopped eating
meat &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; eggs &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; cheese &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; milk and really anything non-vegan!
Someone who keeps this kind of company... I mean, that's kind of extreme
to live in France and not eat Coq-au-Vin, cheese, baguette and more wine
every evening, isn't it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-don-t-watch-television-and-don-t-go-to-the-movies-anymore-because-they-show-images-i-consider-forbidden"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I don't watch television and don't go to the movies anymore (because they show images I consider forbidden)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait, I say, it's just that 99% of TV is bullshit or just plain shit.
Not worth spending a single second on. And I stay at work too late to go
to the movies. And my French is not good enough anyway... Ha, you say,
what pitiful pretexts to avoid sinful imagery! And right you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-stopped-doing-sports-because-it-is-mixed-gender"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I stopped doing Sports (because it is mixed-gender)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or because I am a classic Computer Science nerd who's idea of a good
evening can involve lengthy research on a topic remotely relevant to nothing, really,
followed by a rant on some remote social network most
people have not even heard of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I score &lt;strong&gt;6 out of 9&lt;/strong&gt; on this list, and &amp;quot;started wearing
clothes that cover the whole body&amp;quot; doesn't really count when Grenoble is
just having the first real snow.
Also I am not a women! (you can note this as &amp;quot;has medieval understanding of gender equality&amp;quot;)
So I guess I am pretty dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="but-wait-there-is-more"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;But wait, there is more!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="An icon of the false belief in total security." class="align-right" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-02-04_vigipirate.jpg" style="width: 200px;" /&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spend &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of time alone, thinking, reading, writing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I definitely have a problem with authority. I am &lt;em&gt;outraged&lt;/em&gt; by the
pointless demonstration of... of what, really?... at the entry door
at work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I live in a students accommodation, but I hardly meet my neighbors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, I could try and explain all of these points away, but let's
face it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The Red Menace is real! Report all suspected communist activity!" class="align-left" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-02-04_red_menace.jpg" style="height: 200px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This list is BULLSHIT&lt;/strong&gt; because it assumes you to know the motivation
behind someone's actions.
If you don't, it conveniently delivers the &amp;quot;correct&amp;quot; interpretation with the observations.
Sure, the disclaimer &lt;em&gt;at the bottom of the page&lt;/em&gt; notes that every case has to be treated individually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But overall, this kind of list makes any &amp;quot;unnormal&amp;quot; behaviour suspicious in and of itself.
The mindset this list promotes runs counter to the idea of individualism that I love so much about our western values or what they are supposed to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list only serves to spread &lt;strong&gt;Fear, Uncertainty and Doubt&lt;/strong&gt;.
But then, that's what a sleeper terrorist would say, wouldn't he?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, that's also what a communist would say around 1920 or during
the McCarthy era.
Or a witch a few hundred years before that...
Recommended reading of the day: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Crucible"&gt;The Crucible&lt;/a&gt; by Arthur Miller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt;
To the people shouting &amp;quot;Daan, don't be paranoid, nobody is going to say you're a terrorist&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point here was to demonstrate that this list can be applied to nearly anyone.
And when it comes to terrorists, a perceived intention seems to be good enough nowadays to treat you like one.
That means that this kind of criteria can easily be applied to people sho don't fit the social norm, or to anyone else, to make them &amp;quot;disappear&amp;quot; from public opinion.
In Germany they now want to take away passports of people &lt;em&gt;they think might want to&lt;/em&gt; leave to fight for IS/SIS/ISIL.
These people would then get a &amp;quot;replacement&amp;quot; passport which is basically saying &amp;quot;we think this person might be  a terrorist.&amp;quot;
Good luck getting a job with one o these.
How would you feel if the country you lived in took away your passport and branded you a dengerous person?
Chances are, you would be angry, aren't they?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, making people snitch on others for not fitting social norms &lt;em&gt;based on a perceived intention&lt;/em&gt; is dangerous because it will marginalize these people and may very well create the very aggression against society it is supposed to stifle.
But then again, that's the essence of the War on Terror™: you fight it with extreme means, so that you can be sure to prove yourself right in saying there are lots of enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Terrorism"></category><category term="France"></category><category term="Bullshit"></category><category term="FUD"></category></entry></feed>