<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Some Personal Notes</title><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/feeds/war-on-democracy.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://black-puppydog.github.io/</id><updated>2015-05-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>All Remedies Available, Part II</title><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/all-remedies-available-part-ii.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Daan Wynen</name></author><id>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-05-17:all-remedies-available-part-ii.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today Ars Technica has a short &lt;a href="http://arstechnica.co.uk/tech-policy/2015/05/uk-government-quietly-rewrites-hacking-laws-to-grant-gchq-immunity/"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; about a new law "that exempts GCHQ, police, and other intelligence officers from prosecution for hacking into computers and mobile phones."
Effectively this makes (some of) the things that Edward Snowden made us aware of legal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why would the public accept this kind of thing to pass?
Why didn't we hear about this earlier?
How come this was not a hot topic for debate?
That's the thing with this law: nobody was told it even existed &lt;em&gt;until it was already in effect&lt;/em&gt;!
As Ars Technica points out, this is legal.
That is, the current (and past) laws in the UK allow for this kind of thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But secret laws are (another) way the UK government is rapidly deconstructing their image as a democratic group, i.e. a group that practices democratic procedures in the public interest.
Apart from government, intelligence and law enforcement agencies, nobody could influence this legislation.
So who is being represented here?
For me, a government that does this kind of thing loses its legitimacy, full stop.
And this becomes even more drastic seeing that this bit of news breaks just a week after the elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about this in the context of my short look at the &lt;a href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/camerons-dystopia.html"&gt;right to resistance&lt;/a&gt; from Thursday:
When have we used the available remedies?
Well, for a law that atacks the individual's freedoms, is passed in secret, and held secret until in effect, there are &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; few in the first place..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this kind of action the UK government makes it easy to pursue arguments that legitimize extremist actions by taking away most of, if not all, remedies that would be available through a proper democratic debate.
If that was not their intention then they should revoke this law, enter it into the proper parliamentary process and pass it with a vote the public can see and judge them by.
If it &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; their intention, then the UK would already be it's own version of 1984 that easily legitimizes any act against Big Brother.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Democracy"></category><category term="GCHQ"></category><category term="UK"></category></entry><entry><title>Cameron's Dystopia</title><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/camerons-dystopia.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Daan Wynen</name></author><id>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-05-14:camerons-dystopia.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I first read about this in the &lt;a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/britain-is-too-tolerant-and-should-interfere-more-in-peoples-lives-says-david-cameron-10246517.html"&gt;Independent&lt;/a&gt; I thought they must have gotten something wrong.
But no, &lt;a href="https://firstlook.org/theintercept/2015/05/13/greatest-threat-free-speech-comes-terrorism-claiming-fight/"&gt;The Intercept&lt;/a&gt; and the Guardian heard the same words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This actually seems to be David Cameron's stance on what a democracy should look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For too long, we have been a passively tolerant society, saying to our citizens 'as long as you obey the law, we will leave you alone.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's right, being within your rights to do something is no longer an excuse for doing it.
To enforce this outrageous attack on democracy you obviously would need to control what people think, or rather which kind of opinion can even spread and thus (to an extent) which kind of thoughts can form in your &lt;strike&gt;subordinates'&lt;/strike&gt; citizens' minds.
Here you go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim is to catch not just those who spread or incite hatred on the grounds of gender, race or religion but also those who undertake harmful activities for the “purpose of overthrowing democracy”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They would include a ban on broadcasting and a requirement to submit to the police in advance any proposed publication on the web and social media or in print&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tory Home Secretary Theresa May, in context of what would constitute "extremism" only talks about people who "undermine our British values" and being "together as one society, One Nation."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greenwald:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally believe this was all more lyrical in its original German&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I agree. Also, some of the politicians giving the original speeches had much more charisma...
But the point is: Germany learned from this experience. 
So even if it obviously doesn't apply in the UK, let's have a look at that.
The German constitution contains an unamendable paragraph that deals with the very issue Cameron and his thugs claim to address: 
"overthrowing democracy":&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Germans shall have the right to resist any person seeking to abolish this constitutional order, if no other remedy is available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's right: Cameron's plan, if implemented, could easily fall under Germany's right to resistance &lt;em&gt;and vice versa&lt;/em&gt;!
A citizen fighting for their right to free expression could easily be labelled an extremist and faced with who knows what kind of treatment (&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/law/2014/jul/22/terrorism-law-targets-words-guns-bombs"&gt;David Miranda&lt;/a&gt; might have a word to say about that) because fundamentally disagreeing with your government is supposedly the most unbritish thing one could do.
But look at the issue from the other direction, the one expressed in the German constitution, and you get the complete opposite.
The UK government wants to...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;outlaw opinions - even those expressed in a civil, nonviolent manner - and brand those expressing them "extremists". Which opinions? Unbritish ones!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make submission to the police of virtually &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; content &lt;em&gt;before publication&lt;/em&gt; mandatory (But "only" for people who have drawn attention before. And remember, the UK does not protect the freedom of the press in their constitution)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reintroduce laws for data retention under the "&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Draft_Communications_Data_Bill"&gt;Snoopers' Charter&lt;/a&gt;". Because, how else would epople "draw attention"? Due process or what?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a lawyer, but I am German. And funnily, that gives me an edge here for once.
After years of history lessons in highschool, criminalizing "unbritish" behaviour &lt;em&gt;and opinions&lt;/em&gt; for me is a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; red flag in terms of "overthrowing democracy". &lt;br/&gt;
But when is it really okay to conclude that the government has indeed set out to abolish democracy?
Where is the red line? &lt;br/&gt;
There is one more caveat with the right to resistance: you need to have used all other remedies.
When can you claim to have used the remedies available to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take this &lt;a href="http://www.spiegel.de/netzwelt/netzpolitik/angela-merkel-luegt-dem-volk-ist-es-egal-lobo-kolumne-a-1033577.html"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; (in German, sorry) by Sascha Lobo, incidentally also from yesterday.
Lobo complains (IMHO rightfully) that all the free press, all the evidence against our politicians is worthless if people can not be mobilized to vote those politicians out of office.
When the people disagreeing with the current government see no alternatives, when they are so disillusioned with politics as a whole that they see no point in trying to change anything, then the best evidence of even criminal actions &lt;em&gt;by our government&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;against us&lt;/em&gt; will remain without consequence.
The "fourth estate" becomes an exercise in futility.
And also, a population that cannot be bothered to vote loses its right to resistance.
You could have voted your tyrants out of power you lazy bums!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- ![Guy Fawkes Mask]({filename}/images/2015&amp;#45;05&amp;#45;14_guy_fawkes.jpg) --&gt;

&lt;figure style="float: right"&gt;
    &lt;img alt="Original Guy Fawks mask from V for Vendetta" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-05-14_guy_fawkes.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt; &lt;a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Original_Guy_Fawks_mask_from_V_for_Vendetta_%285400848923%29.jpg" &gt;CC-BY Enrique Dans&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the case of the UK, the plans are published just days &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the election.
By the time of the next election, publicly fighting such core British values as internet, media and thought censorship might already be illegal.
And those opposing the law now?
Well, they are against a law aiming to catch "those who spread or incite hatred on the grounds of gender, race or religion".
They should probably submit their social media posts to the police for good measure.
So where's the remedy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's hope people won't have to remember where those masks came from.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Cameron"></category><category term="UK"></category><category term="Free Speech"></category></entry><entry><title>Das Problem ist der Wütende Mob!</title><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/altenbockum-erklaert-den-mob-zum-problem.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Daan Wynen</name></author><id>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-04-26:altenbockum-erklaert-den-mob-zum-problem.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Für die, dies es nicht mitbekommen haben: &lt;a href="http://www.spiegel.de/politik/deutschland/ueberwachung-neue-spionageaffaere-erschuettert-bnd-a-1030191.html"&gt;Spiegel Online&lt;/a&gt; berichtete am Donnerstag darüber, dass der BND jahrelang &lt;em&gt;wissentlich&lt;/em&gt; Selektoren der NSA verheimlicht hat, die klar gegen europäische und deutsche Ziele gerichtet waren, und nicht etwa gegen Terroristen oder dergleichen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In der &lt;a href="http://www.faz.net/aktuell/politik/kommentar-der-bnd-im-circus-maximus-13557254.html"&gt;FAZ&lt;/a&gt; erklärt Japser von Altenbockum, was das eigentliche Problem derzeit ist:
Es ist nicht etwa das Auspionieren von Europäischen und Deutschen Unternehmen, Politikern und (IMHO stets unterbewertet) Privatpersonen, nein.
Genau genommen gibt es eigentlich gar kein Problem. 
Der BND hat sich nur im falschen Augenblick einen Fauxpas geleistet, indem er der Bundesregierung nichts von den Selektoren gesagt hat, die klar nichts mit Terrorismus zu tun hatten.
Das macht den Mob - die "aufgepeitschte Öffentlichkeit" - wütend, das war "eine Dummheit".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dieser Artikel macht mich sauer, und das gleich aus mehreren Gründen.
Gleich zu Beginn stellt Altenbockum den Strohmann auf, die NSA sei "die größte Bedrohung der deutschen Sicherheit" und schießt diesen dann folgermaßen nieder:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ohne diese Zusammenarbeit wäre die Sicherheit Deutschlands gefährdet. Da das so ist, haben alle diese Angriffe für die Arbeit des BND untergeordnete Bedeutung. Viel wichtiger sind: Russland, China, Terror. Ein Versäumnis in dieser Richtung wäre weit gravierender als alle bisher bekannt gewordenen Versäumnisse des BND an der Seite der NSA zusammengenommen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wohlgemerkt schreibt er &lt;em&gt;nicht&lt;/em&gt;, dass das schon alles seine Ordnung gehabt hätte.
Sondern er sagt im Grunde "aber wir können uns im Kampf gegen den Terror (und Russland und China) von solchen Kleinlichkeiten wie geltendem Recht nicht aufhalten lassen."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Das alleine wäre mir schon zuwider, denn mit desem Statement hätte Herr von Altenbockum auch einfach Regierungssprecher werden können.
Aber dann macht er sich noch nicht einmal die Mühe, das vernünftig auszuformulieren.
"Russland, China, Terror."
Bloß nicht zu kompliziert, der Mob braucht schließlich ein klar definiertes Feindbild.
Alles andere verwirrt den Mob nur, könnte ihn gar aufpeitschen.
Daher auch gleich noch eine Ansage dazu, was von den bisherigen Veröffentlichungen zu halten ist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alle sensationsheischenden Einblicke in die Welt von BND und NSA mussten zudem – nicht ganz so öffentlichkeitswirksam – korrigiert werden. &lt;a href="http://www.faz.net/aktuell/politik/harte-bretter/ueberwachungsstaat-deutschland-in-der-snowden-falle-13459674.html"&gt;Manche „Massenüberwachung“ entpuppte sich als pure Chimäre&lt;/a&gt;, ohne dass deren Enthüller das bis heute wahrhaben wollten. Auch im jetzt wieder aufgewärmten Fall ist das so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh? Ist das so? Da hängt ein Link dran, das muss ja dann eine Quelle sein, andere Links gibt es im ganzen Kommentar nicht.
Nun, der Link führt zu einem weiteren Kommentar von von Altenbockum, vom 5.3.2015.
In diesem Kommentar stellt er fest, dass im Grunde alles, was Greenwald und andere Journalisten veröffentlichten, Unfug ist.
Eine Quelle dafür gibt er nur in einem Fall: den Gemalto-Hack.
Als Hinweis dafür, dass es sich hierbei ja nur um einen Plan gehandlet haben könnte und nicht etwa um eine vollzogene Attacke, verweist er auf den "Blogger Rolf Weber".
Dieser schrieb im Wesentlichen "seht her, die interessieren sich ja vor allem für SIMs aus dem Iran, Pakistan etc, also alles kein Problem" und berief sich dabei auf &lt;a href="https://firstlook.org/theintercept/document/2015/02/19/imsis-identified-ki-data-network-providers-jan10-mar10-trial/"&gt;eine Folie des GHCQ&lt;/a&gt; (Kopie &lt;a href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-04-26_gemalto_2.pdf"&gt;hier&lt;/a&gt;).
Das als Ausrede gelten zu lassen ist schon ein starkes Stück, vor allem, wenn man sich eine weitere - ebenfalls vom Intercept veröffentlichte - &lt;a href="https://firstlook.org/theintercept/document/2015/02/19/cne-access-core-mobile-networks-2/"&gt;Folie&lt;/a&gt; ( &lt;a href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-04-26_gemalto.pdf"&gt;Kopie&lt;/a&gt;) ansieht:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GEMALTO - successfully implanted several machines and
believe we have their entire network - TDSD are working the
data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Wir haben das gesamte Netz."
Nur gut, dass wir uns darauf verlassen können, dass sie nicht hinter uns her sind, schließlich ist Gemalto der weltweit größte Hersteller von SIM-Karten.
Wann und warum die anderen angesprochenen Enthüllungen - Prism und Boundless Informant werden als Beipsiele gegeben - so nicht stimmen, wird gar nicht weiter belegt. Muss man ja auch nicht, das hier reicht da schon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Falsch war auch, dass die NSA direkten Zugang zu den Servern amerikanischer Internetkonzerne wie Apple oder Google hatte („Prism“)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noch Fragen? Keine? Gut, dann jetzt zurück zum Kommentar von letztem Freitag, 24.4.
Nachdem Altenbockum mit Hinweis auf seine eigenen, größtenteils unbelegten Aussagen, klargestellt hat, dass es kein Problem gibt, kann man dann ja der Linkspartei "politische Geschmacklosigkeit" und Antiamerikanismus vorzuwerfen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im letzten Absatz macht von Altenbockum dann noch einmal klar, was genau man dem BND vorwerfen sollte und was nicht, und nebenbei wiederholt er noch einmal wie gefährlich die Lage für Deutschland doch ist:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Das Kanzleramt über faule NSA-Eier nicht zu informieren, mag angesichts der wahren Bedrohungslage Deutschlands verständlich gewesen sein. Doch allein, dass die SPD die Gelegenheit nutzt, die Kanzlerin zu schwächen, kann der BND-Spitze schon aus Eigeninteresse nicht gleichgültig sein. Angesichts der politischen Bedrohungslage des Kanzleramts war es deshalb eine Dummheit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soso, es war mag also verständlich gewesen sein, die Regierung &lt;em&gt;nicht&lt;/em&gt; auf klar gegen Deutsche und Europäische Interessen gerichtete Abfragen der NSA hinzuweisen und ihr damit die Basis zu einer echten Entscheidungsgrundlage zu nehmen?
Da muss man doch sogleich an einen Satz aus dem Absatz direkt darüber denken:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ein Geheimdienst, der sich gegen den eigenen Staat richtet und der sich dessen Kontrolle entzieht, ist ein Risiko für jede freie Gesellschaft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wenn unser eigener Nachrichtendienst es nicht für berichtenswert hält, dass unsere vermeintlich Verbündeten ihn zu Spionagezwecken &lt;em&gt;gegen uns selber&lt;/em&gt; missbrauchen, dann haben wir ein großes Problem. 
Journalisten wie Herr von Altenbockum, die in ihrem Glauben an das Wohlwollen der USA und unserer eigenen Dienste so aufgehen, dass sie deren Parolen (Bedrohungslage! Bedrohliche Bedrohungslage!) und Feindbilder (China! Russland! Terror!) dermaßen unhinterfragt und überspitzt wiederholen, sind ebenfalls Teil des Problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ach und der Mob ist auch nicht wütend. Das ist Zorn.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="NSA"></category><category term="BND"></category><category term="FAZ"></category></entry><entry><title>French Media on the Arrest of (yet another) Artist</title><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/zeon.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Daan Wynen</name></author><id>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-03-26:zeon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you heard of Zeon?
Well, I heard about him today, &lt;a href="http://nonalignedmedia.com/2015/03/french-cartoonist-zeon-arrested-anti-zionist-work/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short version: he makes cartoons.
Which is what he got arrested for.
Or rather, for hatespeech. In his cartoons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you might disagree with his views, the whole Charlie affair should still be fresh enough for people to remember what this freedom of expression stuff is supposed to mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link above is from &lt;strong&gt;March 4&lt;/strong&gt; so by now this kind of case should have been properly discussed by the media.
So, these are the search results (from today, &lt;strong&gt;March 26&lt;/strong&gt;, 2015) for &lt;strong&gt;"Zeon"&lt;/strong&gt; in the French mainstream media as defined by &lt;a href="http://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Presse_en_France"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Le Parisien&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Le Parisien" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_leparisien.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are close! But not quite the right artist...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Le Figaro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Le Figaro" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lefigaro.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Le Monde&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Le Monde" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lemonde.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;L'Équipe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="L'Équipe" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lequipe.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I didn't really expect to find anything relevant there...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Les Échos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Les Échos" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lesechos.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Libération&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Libération" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_liberation.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;La Croix&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="La Croix" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lacroix.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;L'Humanité&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="L'Humanité" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-03-26_lhumanite.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charlie Wassissname again?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Free Speech"></category><category term="France"></category><category term="Media"></category></entry><entry><title>Holy Crap, I am Dangerous!</title><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/am-i-a-terrorist.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Daan Wynen</name></author><id>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-02-04:am-i-a-terrorist.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to this list from the French Government I am in high
danger to become a jihadist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://static2.stop-djihadisme.gouv.fr/var/stop/storage/images/media/images/radicalisation/607-6-fre-FR/radicalisation.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="A handy list to check if everyone around you will become a jihadist." class="align-right" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-02-04_france_radicalisation.png" style="width: 30%;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So do both of us a favor and report me,
will you? Not convinced? Let me walk you through the list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-keep-a-distance-to-my-former-friends-because-i-consider-them-impure"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I keep a distance to my former friends (because I consider them &amp;quot;impure&amp;quot;)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True, I recently moved to a different country, so that might be it.
Except, you don't &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; why I left everyone behind...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-reject-family-members"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I reject Family Members&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't talked to some of them in &lt;em&gt;months&lt;/em&gt;. Sure, I would say I feel
bad about that. But would you believe someone who so obviously doesn't
give a jihadist shit about his family?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-brutally-changed-my-eating-habits"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I brutally changed my eating habits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I may or may not have changed from &amp;quot;cook your own meals to take to
work&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;eat in the canteen, then live off
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ramen"&gt;ramen&lt;/a&gt; at home.&amp;quot; But some of my
friends are also very suspicious: One of them recently stopped eating
meat &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; eggs &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; cheese &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; milk and really anything non-vegan!
Someone who keeps this kind of company... I mean, that's kind of extreme
to live in France and not eat Coq-au-Vin, cheese, baguette and more wine
every evening, isn't it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-don-t-watch-television-and-don-t-go-to-the-movies-anymore-because-they-show-images-i-consider-forbidden"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I don't watch television and don't go to the movies anymore (because they show images I consider forbidden)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait, I say, it's just that 99% of TV is bullshit or just plain shit.
Not worth spending a single second on. And I stay at work too late to go
to the movies. And my French is not good enough anyway... Ha, you say,
what pitiful pretexts to avoid sinful imagery! And right you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="i-stopped-doing-sports-because-it-is-mixed-gender"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I stopped doing Sports (because it is mixed-gender)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or because I am a classic Computer Science nerd who's idea of a good
evening can involve lengthy research on a topic remotely relevant to nothing, really,
followed by a rant on some remote social network most
people have not even heard of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I score &lt;strong&gt;6 out of 9&lt;/strong&gt; on this list, and &amp;quot;started wearing
clothes that cover the whole body&amp;quot; doesn't really count when Grenoble is
just having the first real snow.
Also I am not a women! (you can note this as &amp;quot;has medieval understanding of gender equality&amp;quot;)
So I guess I am pretty dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="but-wait-there-is-more"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;But wait, there is more!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="An icon of the false belief in total security." class="align-right" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-02-04_vigipirate.jpg" style="width: 200px;" /&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spend &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of time alone, thinking, reading, writing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I definitely have a problem with authority. I am &lt;em&gt;outraged&lt;/em&gt; by the
pointless demonstration of... of what, really?... at the entry door
at work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I live in a students accommodation, but I hardly meet my neighbors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, I could try and explain all of these points away, but let's
face it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="The Red Menace is real! Report all suspected communist activity!" class="align-left" src="https://black-puppydog.github.io/images/2015-02-04_red_menace.jpg" style="height: 200px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This list is BULLSHIT&lt;/strong&gt; because it assumes you to know the motivation
behind someone's actions.
If you don't, it conveniently delivers the &amp;quot;correct&amp;quot; interpretation with the observations.
Sure, the disclaimer &lt;em&gt;at the bottom of the page&lt;/em&gt; notes that every case has to be treated individually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But overall, this kind of list makes any &amp;quot;unnormal&amp;quot; behaviour suspicious in and of itself.
The mindset this list promotes runs counter to the idea of individualism that I love so much about our western values or what they are supposed to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list only serves to spread &lt;strong&gt;Fear, Uncertainty and Doubt&lt;/strong&gt;.
But then, that's what a sleeper terrorist would say, wouldn't he?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, that's also what a communist would say around 1920 or during
the McCarthy era.
Or a witch a few hundred years before that...
Recommended reading of the day: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Crucible"&gt;The Crucible&lt;/a&gt; by Arthur Miller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt;
To the people shouting &amp;quot;Daan, don't be paranoid, nobody is going to say you're a terrorist&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point here was to demonstrate that this list can be applied to nearly anyone.
And when it comes to terrorists, a perceived intention seems to be good enough nowadays to treat you like one.
That means that this kind of criteria can easily be applied to people sho don't fit the social norm, or to anyone else, to make them &amp;quot;disappear&amp;quot; from public opinion.
In Germany they now want to take away passports of people &lt;em&gt;they think might want to&lt;/em&gt; leave to fight for IS/SIS/ISIL.
These people would then get a &amp;quot;replacement&amp;quot; passport which is basically saying &amp;quot;we think this person might be  a terrorist.&amp;quot;
Good luck getting a job with one o these.
How would you feel if the country you lived in took away your passport and branded you a dengerous person?
Chances are, you would be angry, aren't they?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, making people snitch on others for not fitting social norms &lt;em&gt;based on a perceived intention&lt;/em&gt; is dangerous because it will marginalize these people and may very well create the very aggression against society it is supposed to stifle.
But then again, that's the essence of the War on Terror™: you fight it with extreme means, so that you can be sure to prove yourself right in saying there are lots of enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="Terrorism"></category><category term="France"></category><category term="Bullshit"></category><category term="FUD"></category></entry></feed>