<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Some Personal Notes</title><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/feeds/web.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://black-puppydog.github.io/</id><updated>2015-02-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>User Tracking goes deeper than Ads</title><link href="https://black-puppydog.github.io/subscription-based-publishing-wont-solve-tracking-and-profiling.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Daan Wynen</name></author><id>tag:black-puppydog.github.io,2015-02-13:subscription-based-publishing-wont-solve-tracking-and-profiling.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is just something I picked up some time ago while attending &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lukOlejnik"&gt;Łukasz Olejnik&lt;/a&gt;'s PhD defense "Measuring the Privacy Risks and Value of Web Tracking".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He basically said that the problem with the advertising market form a privacy perspective is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the advertising itself but the tracking and profiling that comes with it.
Obvious as that might seem, in my mind I had always thrown the two into the same pot, probably also because after yars without a TV or thelike I am easily annoyed by any advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this simple insight leads Łuskasz to another one that is more profound:&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Getting rid of the ads won't automatically solve the privacy issues.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscription-based publishing is one of the alternatives to advertising and often presented as more privacy-friendly.
But what would happen if this model actually got adopted on a larger scale?
Most probably, according to Łukasz, third-party services would quickly emerge to handle the subscription-management across sites.
And just like the would a very similar situation as before:
A handful of people/companies would know who pays for which subscriptions, reads which articles, loads which images.
Just like today's advertising industry they would be able to track and profile through cookies and &lt;a href="https://panopticlick.eff.org/"&gt;all other means available&lt;/a&gt;
It would just look less annoying because of the missing ads.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Web"></category><category term="Privacy"></category></entry></feed>